In the last video, you saw
the basic search algorithm,
in this video, you learn
some little changes,
they'll make it
work even better.
Length normalization is a small
change to the beam search,
however, they can help you
get much better results.
Here's what it is, we
talked about beam search
as maximizing this
probability and
this product here is just
expressing the
observation that p
of y1 up to yt y given x
can be expressed as p
of y1 given x times p
of y2 given x and
y1 times up to,
I guess, p y ty given x
and y1 up to y ty minus 1.
But maybe this notation is a bit
more scary and more intimidating
than it needs to be,
but is that probabilities
that you've seen previously.
Now, if you're
implementing these,
these probabilities
are all numbers
less than one, in fact,
often they're much less than
one and multiplying a lot
of numbers less than one
result in a tiny number,
which can result in
numerical under-floor,
meaning that is too small
for the floating point of
representation in your
computer to store accurately.
In practice, instead of
maximizing this product,
we will take logs and if
you insert a log there,
then a log of a product
becomes a sum of a log,
and maximizing this sum of
log probabilities should
give you the same
results in terms
of selecting the most
likely sentence.
By taking logs,
you end up with a more
numerically stable algorithm
that is less prone
to numerical rounding errors
or really numerical under-floor.
Because the logarithmic
function is
a strictly monotonically
increasing function,
we know that maximizing
log p of y given x should
give you the same result as
maximizing p of y given
x as in the same value
of y that maximizes,
this should also maximize that.
In most implementations,
you keep track of the sum
of logs of the probabilities
rather than the product
of probabilities.
Now there's one other change to
this objective
function that makes
the machine translation
algorithm work even better.
Which is that if
you refer to this original
objective up here,
if you have a very
long sentence,
the probability of that
sentence is going to be low
because you're multiplying
as many terms here,
lots of numbers less than one
to estimate the probability
of that sentence.
If you multiply
log of the numbers
less than one together,
you just tend to end up
with a smaller probability.
This objective function has
an undesirable effect that
it may be unnaturally
tend to prefer
very short
translations to prefer
very short outputs because
the probability of
a short sentence is
just by multiplying fewer
of these numbers are
less than one and
so the product will just
be not quite as small.
By the way, the same
thing is true for this,
the log of a probability is
always less than
or equal to one,
you're actually in
this range of the log,
so the more terms
you add together,
the more negative
this thing becomes.
There's one other
change the algorithm
that makes it work better,
which is instead
of using this as
the objective you're
trying to maximize.
One thing you could
do is normalizes by
the number of words in
your translation and
so this takes the average
of the log of the probability of
each word and does
significantly
reduces the penalty
for outputting longer translations.
In practice as a heuristic
instead of dividing by
ty the number of words
in the output sentence,
sometimes you use
the softer approach
we have ty to power of
Alpha where maybe
Alpha is equal to 0.7.
If Alpha was equal to one,
then the completely
normalized by length,
if Alpha was equal
to 0, then well,
ty to the 0 will be 1,
then you're just
not normalizing at
all and this is somewhere
in between full normalization
and no normalization.
Alpha is another
parameter hyperparameter,
so the algorithm that you
can tune to try to
get the best results.
Using Alpha this way,
does this heuristic
or does this a hack?
There isn't a great theoretical
justification for it,
but people found
this works well,
people found it
works well in practice,
so many groups won't do this,
and you can try out
different values of
Alpha and see which one
gives you the best result.
Just to wrap up how
you can beam search,
as you run beam search
you see a lot of
sentences with length equal 1,
length sentences were equal 2,
length sentence that
equals 3 and so on,
and maybe you run beam search
for 30 steps you consider,
output sentences
up to 30, let's say.
Would beam width of three,
you would be keeping track of
the top three possibilities for
each of these possible
sentence length 1,
2, 3, 4, and so on up to 30.
Output sentences and score
them against this score
and so you can take
your top sentences
and just computes
this objective function
on the sentences that you
have seen through the
beam search process.
Then finally, of
all these sentences
that you evaluate this way,
you pick the one that achieves,
the highest value on this
normalize low
probability objective,
sometimes it's
called a normalized
log likelihood objective
and then that would be the
final translation you output.
That's how you implement
beam search and you get to
play with this yourself in
this week's
programming exercise.
Finally, a few
implementation details,
how do you choose
the beam width?
Share the pros and cons
of setting beam to be
very large versus very small.
If the beam width is very large,
then you consider a lot of
possibilities and so you
tend to get a better result
because you're considering a
lot of different options,
but it will be slower.
The memory requirements
will also grow and
also be computationally slower.
Whereas if you use a
very small beam width,
then you get a worse result
because you are just keeping
less possibilities in mind
as the algorithm is running,
but you get a result faster and
the memory requirements
will also be lower.
In the previous video,
we use in our running
example a beam width of 3,
so we're keeping three
possibilities in mind in
practice that is on the small
side in production systems,
it's not uncommon to see a
beam width maybe around 10.
I think a beam width
of 100 would be
considered very large
for a production system,
depending on the application.
But for research systems where
people want to squeeze out
every last drop of
performance in order
to publish a paper with the
best possible result,
it's not uncommon
to see people use
beam width of 1,000 or 3,000,
but this is very application
as well as a domain dependent.
I would say try out a
variety of values of
beam as see what works
for your application,
but when beam is very large,
there is often
diminishing returns.
For many applications,
I would expect to see
a huge gain as you
go from beam of one,
which is basically greedy search
to three to maybe 10,
but the gains as you
go from the thousands
to three thousand beam width
might not be as big.
For those of you that have
taken maybe a lot of computer
science courses before,
if you're familiar with computer
science search algorithms
like BFS breadth first search
or DFS depth first search,
the way to think
about beam search is
that unlike those
other algorithms
which you might
have learned about
in computer science
algorithms course,
and don't worry
about it if you've
not heard of these algorithms.
But if you've heard
of breadth first search or depth first search,
unlike those algorithms,
which are exact search
algorithms beam search
runs much faster but is
not guaranteed to find
the exact maximum for
this arg max that
you like to find.
If you haven't heard of
breadth first search or depth first search,
don't worry about it.
It is not important for our purposes,
but if you have, this is how
the beam search relates
to those algorithms.
That's it for beam search,
which is a widely
used algorithm in
many production systems or
many commercial systems.
Now in the third course
in this sequence of courses
on deep learning,
we talk a lot about
error analysis,
it turns out one of the
most useful tools I found
is devoted to error
analysis on beam search,
so you sometimes wonder,
should I increase my beam width?
Is beam width
working well enough
and there are some simple
things we can compute
to give you guidance
on whether you need to
work on improving your
search algorithm.
Let's talk about that
in the next video.